Hello English learners, welcome back to another lesson with us here at EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的又一堂课。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we have a lesson for all our university students out there.
今天这堂课是为我们所有的大学生准备的。
That's right.
没错。
We're talking about registering for university.
我们要讨论的是大学注册。
Okay, so it's a difficult process sometimes even in your own language, so we're going
好的，即使是用母语，这个过程有时也很困难，所以我们
to try and make it a little bit easier by giving you some of the common words you would
会通过提供一些你在大学注册时
need to register at a university.
需要的常用词汇，让它变得稍微容易一些。
Alright, well I think it's time we get started by listening to the dialogue.
好了，我想是时候开始听对话了。
And we're going to listen to a young female student as she tries to choose her classes.
我们将听到一位年轻女学生试图选课的场景。
Excuse me, is this where I register?
打扰一下，是在这里注册吗？
I'd like to sign up for my courses for next semester.
我想报名下学期的课程。
Yes, of course.
是的，当然。
I need your student ID please.
请给我你的学生证。
Here you are.
给你。
Okay, Susan.
好的，Susan。
It says here that you are a business major and that you're in your second year.
这里显示你是商科专业，现在是第二年。
Is this information correct?
这些信息正确吗？
Yes.
是的。
I do want to take some additional credits this year to get a minor in psychology.
我今年想多修一些学分，辅修心理学。
Sure, that's not a problem.
当然，没问题。
Do you have a list of courses that you want to take this semester?
你这学期有想选的课程清单吗？
Yeah, here's my list.
有，这是我的清单。
I'm not sure if the class schedule will allow me to take all of them though.
不过我不确定课程表能不能让我全部修完。
Yeah, that's perfect.
嗯，这很好。
What about the subjects for your minor?
那辅修科目呢？
Oh yeah, I almost forgot.
哦对，我差点忘了。
I need to take fundamental linguistics, consumer psychology, and neuroanatomy.
我需要修基础语言学、消费者心理学和神经解剖学。
Wow, you're going to be busy this semester.
哇，你这学期会很忙啊。
Okay, here you go.
好了，给你。
You're registered now.
你现在已经注册好了。
You have to make your first tuition payment before classes start.
你需要在开课前支付第一笔学费。
All right, great, a very good student taking a lot of classes this semester.
好的，很棒，一个非常好的学生这学期要上很多课。
I know, and it sounds like some of them are pretty hard as well.
我知道，而且听起来有些课还挺难的。
Yeah, they are.
是啊，确实如此。
Well, she used some of those very common phrases that we would need when we are registering
嗯，她用到了一些我们在大学注册时
at university.
非常常见的短语。
So let's take a look at them now in Language Takeaway.
那我们现在就在“语言要点”环节来看看它们。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay.
好的。
So, the first thing, I think we need to deal with this word to register.
那么，第一件事，我觉得我们需要处理这个词“注册”。
Register.
注册。
So register for university.
所以是大学注册。
Okay, so we've mentioned this word many times, so I think it would be a good idea to listen
好的，我们之前多次提到这个词，所以我觉得最好先听
to some examples and then we'll come back and explain it.
一些例子，然后我们再回来解释。
Example one.
例子一。
I registered to attend the conference on international trade this month.
我注册参加了这个月的国际贸易会议。
Example two.
例子二。
It is your obligation as a good citizen to register to vote.
作为好公民，你有义务注册投票。
Example three.
例子三。
It is necessary to register on our website before joining the conference.
在参加会议之前，有必要在我们的网站上注册。
So when you register for something, you put your name down on a list, right?
所以当你注册某件事时，就是把你的名字列在名单上，对吧？
So in this case, when you register for university, you officially put your name on the list of
那么在这种情况下，当你注册大学时，就是正式把你的名字列在
students in that course.
那门课程的学生名单上。
Okay, so you can register for university.
好的，所以你可以注册大学。
What else can you register for?
你还能注册什么？
Register for a class.
注册一门课。
You can even register to vote.
你甚至可以注册投票。
Okay, so register.
好的，所以是注册。
Now she was registering for her classes and we saw these words that we know already, but
现在她正在注册课程，我们看到了这些我们已经知道的词，但
it's a good idea to take a look at them.
最好还是再看一下。
We heard that she is a business major.
我们听到她是商科专业。
So a major.
所以是专业。
A major.
专业。
A business major.
商科专业。
And what is your major?
你的专业是什么？
The major is the major area that you study, the most important area that you study.
专业就是你学习的主要领域，你最重要的学习领域。
The area where you are specialized.
你专攻的领域。
Yeah, the area that you focus on.
是的，你专注的领域。
Okay, now we heard another one that's called a minor.
好的，现在我们听到另一个词叫辅修。
So this is another area that you study, but it is less important than your major.
所以这是你学习的另一个领域，但比你的专业次要一些。
Okay, so major and your minor.
好的，所以是专业和辅修。
So let's give an example.
那么我们来举个例子。
Imagine you must take 100 classes to graduate from university.
想象一下，你必须修100门课才能从大学毕业。
Maybe you have to take 50 for your major and maybe 30 for your minor.
也许你需要修50门专业课程和30门辅修课程。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And now on your degree, on your title, does it say what is your major and minor?
那么在你的学位证书上，在你的头衔上，会写明你的专业和辅修吗？
Well, I think it depends on the university, but in my case, yes.
嗯，我觉得这取决于大学，但就我而言，是的。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So major and minor.
所以是主修和辅修。
Now related to this and what you were saying about your classes, it takes us to our next
现在，与此相关以及你刚才提到的课程内容，就引出了我们下一个
word, which is credits.
词，也就是学分。
Credits.
学分。
Now, this is easily confused with classes sometimes.
这个词有时容易和课程混淆。
That's right.
没错。
Well, a credit is kind of a point.
嗯，学分有点像一种点数。
So like maybe, so in university, you need a certain number of credits or points to graduate.
比如，在大学里，你需要一定数量的学分或点数才能毕业。
Okay, so suppose you need 100 credits to graduate.
好的，假设你需要100个学分才能毕业。
So that's not 100 courses because each course might be worth four or six or eight credits
那可不是100门课，因为每门课可能值4个、6个或8个学分，
depending on how important it is.
取决于它的重要性。
Very good.
非常好。
So maybe the classes that are part of your major will have more credits.
所以，属于你主修的课程可能会有更多学分。
All right, very good.
好的，非常好。
So, and now we have our last word in this dialogue and it was tuition.
那么，现在我们有了这段对话中的最后一个词，就是学费。
Tuition.
学费。
She had to pay her tuition.
她得付学费。
So tuition is the money that you must pay for education.
所以学费是你为教育必须支付的钱。
Okay, only for education.
好的，只针对教育。
That's right.
没错。
So, university tuition, private school tuition or even language course tuition.
所以，大学学费、私立学校学费，甚至语言课程学费。
Okay, so a tuition is the money you must pay for school only.
好的，所以学费是你只为上学必须支付的钱。
Yeah.
是的。
So we've seen a lot of great words used for registering at university.
我们看到了很多用于大学注册的好词。
So I think it's time to listen to the dialogue for the second time a little bit slower and
所以我觉得是时候再听一遍对话了，这次会慢一点，
then we'll come back and take a look at some phrases.
然后我们再回来看看一些短语。
Excuse me, is this where I register?
打扰一下，是在这里注册吗？
I'd like to sign up for my courses for next semester.
我想报名下学期的课程。
Yes, of course.
是的，当然。
I need your student ID, please.
请给我你的学生证。
Here you are.
给你。
Okay, Susan, it says here that you are a business major and that you're in your second year.
好的，苏珊，这里显示你是商科主修，并且是二年级学生。
Is this information correct?
这些信息正确吗？
Yes.
是的。
I do want to take some additional credits this year to get a minor in psychology.
我今年想多修一些学分，辅修心理学。
Sure, that's not a problem.
当然，没问题。
Do you have a list of courses that you want to take this semester?
你这学期想选的课程有列表吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
Here's my list.
这是我的清单。
I'm not sure if the class schedule will allow me to take all of them though.
不过我不确定课程表能不能让我全选这些课。
Yeah, that's perfect.
嗯，那太好了。
What about the subjects for your minor?
那你辅修的专业科目呢？
Oh, yeah.
哦，对。
I almost forgot.
我差点忘了。
I need to take fundamental linguistics, consumer psychology and neuroanatomy.
我需要修基础语言学、消费心理学和神经解剖学。
Wow, you're going to be busy this semester.
哇，你这学期要忙了。
Okay, here you go.
好了，给你。
You're registered now.
你现在已经注册好了。
You have to make your first tuition payment before classes start.
你必须在开课前支付第一笔学费。
All right, so it's time for putting it together.
好了，现在是“整合一下”的环节。
Putting it together.
整合一下。
And we're going to look at some phrases here that we can use to talk about education and
我们要看一些短语，这些短语可以用来谈论教育和
university and we can use them in different ways.
大学，并且我们可以用不同的方式使用它们。
All right, and our first phrase is actually very similar to register.
好的，我们的第一个短语其实和“注册”很相似。
To sign up for something.
报名参加某事。
Okay, I want to sign up for.
好的，我想报名参加。
I'd like to sign up for my courses.
我想报名选我的课程。
I think it would be a good idea if we listen to some examples of how we can use this phrase.
我觉得我们听一些如何使用这个短语的例子会是个好主意。
Example one.
例子一。
I signed up for a one-year gym membership.
我报名参加了一年的健身房会员。
Example two.
例子二。
If you want to assist our meeting, you need to sign up first.
如果你想参加我们的会议，你需要先报名。
Example three.
例子三。
I hate signing up for things online because they just send you spam emails.
我讨厌在网上报名，因为他们只会给你发垃圾邮件。
Okay, so I can see that to sign up for something is to agree to take part in it.
好的，所以我能理解“报名参加某事”就是同意参与其中。
Okay, so it's a little bit more informal than register.
嗯，它比“注册”要更非正式一些。
Yeah, exactly.
对，没错。
Less formal.
不那么正式。
All right.
好的。
So, moving on to our second phrase.
那么，接着看我们的第二个短语。
This is very important because it's often used improperly, right?
这个很重要，因为它经常被用错，对吧？
Yeah, people often make mistakes with this phrase.
是啊，人们经常在这个短语上犯错。
All right, so let's look at this phrase.
好的，那我们来看看这个短语。
Second year.
二年级。
So, she is in her second year.
所以，她现在是二年级。
Now, it seems very simple.
这看起来很简单。
So, why are we explaining this?
那我们为什么还要解释这个呢？
Well, it often gets confused with grade.
嗯，它经常和“年级”这个词混淆。
So, when we talk about university, we talk about first year, second year, third year,
所以，当我们谈论大学时，我们会说第一年、第二年、第三年、
fourth year.
第四年。
We cannot say grade one, grade two, grade three, grade four.
我们不能说一年级、二年级、三年级、四年级。
Or year one, year two.
或者说一年、两年。
No, it's always first year, second year, third year, fourth year.
不，总是说第一年、第二年、第三年、第四年。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
Or last year.
或者说最后一年。
Yeah, last year.
是的，最后一年。
My last year of college.
我大学的最后一年。
Exactly.
没错。
Very good.
非常好。
So, now you know how you can explain to someone what year of college or university you're
所以，现在你知道如何向别人解释你上大学的第几年了，
in.
对吧。
Yes, that's right.
是的，没错。
Very good.
非常好。
And we have one more phrase to you.
我们还有一个短语要告诉你。
And it was when she was getting her class schedule.
就是当她拿到课程表的时候。
So, class schedule.
所以，课程表。
Class schedule.
课程表。
Now, a schedule is the list of things you do at what time.
现在，课程表就是你什么时间做什么事情的一个列表。
Right, so it's the timetable of your day or your week.
对，所以它就是你一天或一周的时间表。
Yep.
嗯。
All right.
好的。
So, your class schedule will say all the classes that you have and what time they're at.
所以，你的课程表会列出你所有的课程以及它们的时间。
So, what other types of schedules can we have?
那么，我们还能有其他什么类型的日程表呢？
You also have maybe a gym schedule.
你可能还有健身计划。
That's right.
没错。
Or even a work schedule.
或者甚至工作安排。
Right.
对。
So, we have different types of schedules and you can use it depending on what you are doing.
所以，我们有不同类型的日程表，你可以根据你正在做的事情来使用它们。
Those are all the phrases we have for putting it together today.
这些就是我们今天要整合的所有短语。
And now, let's listen to the dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back.
现在，让我们最后一次听对话，然后我们再回来。
Excuse me.
打扰一下。
Is this where I register?
这是注册的地方吗？
I'd like to sign up for my courses for next semester.
我想报名下学期的课程。
Yes, of course.
是的，当然。
I need your student ID, please.
我需要你的学生证。
Here you are.
给你。
Okay, Susan.
好的，苏珊。
It says here that you are a business major and that you're in your second year.
这里写着你的专业是商科，而且你正在读大二。
Is this information correct?
这个信息正确吗？
Yes.
是的。
I do want to take some additional credits this year to get a minor in psychology.
我今年确实想多修一些学分，辅修心理学。
Sure.
当然可以。
That's not a problem.
这没问题。
Do you have a list of courses that you want to take this semester?
你这学期想选的课程清单有吗？
Yeah.
有。
Here's my list.
这是我的清单。
I'm not sure if the class schedule will allow me to take all of them, though.
不过我不确定课程表能不能让我全部选上。
Yeah, that's perfect.
嗯，那很好。
What about the subjects for your minor?
那你辅修的科目呢？
Oh, yeah.
哦，对了。
I almost forgot.
我差点忘了。
I need to take fundamental linguistics, consumer psychology, and neuroanatomy.
我需要修基础语言学、消费者心理学和神经解剖学。
Wow.
哇。
You're going to be busy this semester.
你这学期要忙起来了。
Okay, here you go.
好了，给你。
You're registered now.
你现在已经注册好了。
You have to make your first tuition payment before classes start.
你必须在开课前支付第一笔学费。
All right.
好的。
So we were talking about second year, first year, third year, etc.
所以我们刚才在聊大二、大一、大三等等。
Yeah.
嗯。
Now, there are also other names that we give to each year, both for high school and university.
现在，对于每个年级，无论是高中还是大学，我们还有其他的叫法。
And I think this is only for America.
而且我觉得这只有美国才用。
Like in the United States, we don't do this in Canada, and I always get so confused.
比如在美国是这样，但在加拿大我们不这么叫，我总是搞混。
So Marco, what is the name you give to first year students?
那么，Marco，大一学生叫什么？
Okay, so first year students are called freshmen.
好的，大一学生叫freshmen。
Okay, because they're fresh.
嗯，因为他们很新鲜（fresh）。
Because they're fresh.
因为他们很新鲜。
Yeah, they just came from middle school, they just came from high school.
是啊，他们刚从初中或高中毕业过来。
All right.
好的。
And what about the second year students?
那大二学生呢？
They're called sophomores.
他们叫sophomores。
Okay, because they're soft.
嗯，因为他们很软（soft）。
Well, it's not soft.
呃，不是软。
It's a sophomore.
是sophomore。
Like S-O-P-H.
拼写是S-O-P-H。
Sophomore.
Sophomore。
And then third year students are called juniors.
然后大三学生叫juniors。
Okay, because they're almost the, like junior manager.
嗯，因为他们差不多是，比如初级经理。
Exactly.
没错。
Because then last year students are called seniors.
因为最后一年学生叫seniors。
So the oldest guys in the school.
所以是学校里最年长的家伙。
Exactly.
没错。
So you can say, yeah, I'm a sophomore at Arizona State University.
所以你可以说，是啊，我是亚利桑那州立大学的大二学生。
Okay, so we only use this in America though, right?
好的，但这只有美国用，对吧？
Yes, yes.
是的，是的。
And not only for university, but also for high school.
而且不仅大学，高中也用。
Okay.
好的。
All right, guys, that's all the time we have for today.
好了，各位，我们今天的节目时间就到这里。
I hope you enjoyed this lesson.
希望你们喜欢这节课。
And if you have any questions or comments or you want to share with us your experiences
如果你们有任何问题、评论，或者想和我们分享你们在高中或大学的经历，
in high school or university, please come to the website at EnglishPod.com.
请访问我们的网站EnglishPod.com。
That's right.
没错。
So Marco and I are there to answer your questions.
我和Marco会在那里回答你们的问题。
And until next time, thanks for listening and goodbye.
下次再见，感谢收听，再见。
Bye.
再见。